Mother,just once, can we go to lunch...
媽媽,能不能就那麼一次,我們一起吃飯時
...and not talk about what I'm wearing or where my career is going?
你不要談論我的衣著和我的工作
Or who I'm dating.
包括我和誰約會
-Ready for the check? -God,yes.
-準備好買單了? -天哪,是的
-I'll take it. -No,darling.
-我來吧. -不,親愛的
I said I'll take it. Here,take it. Go. Run.
我說了我來.這裡,拿著,走,跑
Very sweet.
真甜蜜啊
-And on what they pay you -Career.
-他們到底為什麼給你工錢. -工作
You don't have to worry about me. I'm doing fine.
你不用擔心我.我做的很好
I'm afraid this has been denied.
我想這張卡被禁用了
That's impossible.
這不可能
That's all right,dear. Here you go.
好吧,親愛的,用這張吧
The One With The Fake Monica
六人行 第1季 第21集 假莫妮卡
-=BT之家DRM小組 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 榮譽出品 河馬根據網絡字幕微調製作
How'd someone get your card number?
怎麼會有人知道你的信用卡號碼?
No idea. Look how much they spent.
我也不知道,你看他們花了多少錢
You only have to pay for the stuff you bought.
你只須付你所買的東西
Still,it's just such reckless spending.
我知道,他真是揮霍無度
When somebody steals...
我想他偷去你的信用卡時
...they've already thrown caution to the wind.
根本就已忘了王法
Wow,what a geek. They spent $69. 95 on a Wonder Mop.
真是個變態,花了69.95元買「神奇拖把」
That's me.
我買的
You see,when I say geek,I mean
你看,我說變態,我的意思是
The hell with it,you bought a $70 mop,you're a geek.
怎麼回事,你花了70塊買一把拖把,你是個變態
Oh,yuck. Ross,he's doing it again.
哦,討厭.羅斯,他又這麼幹了
Marcel,stop humping the lamp.
馬修,別再侵犯那盞燈了
Stop humping. Now,Marcel,come Come here,Marcel.
停止侵犯.現在,馬修,過來,馬修
Oh,no. Not in my room. I'll get him.
不,又到我房裡了,我去抓它出來
You've got to do something about that.
羅斯,你得想辦法阻止
What? It's just a phase.
什麼?這只是個階段
Well,that's what we said about Joey.
我們當時也是這麼說喬伊的
You'd think you would be more understanding.
你們能多給點理解嗎?
I know. But we're not.
我明白.可是我們不能
Would you all relax? It's not that big a deal.
你們冷靜點行嗎?這又沒什麼了不起
-Marcel,stop it. Marcel. Bad monkey. -What?
-馬修,停,壞猴子 -又怎麼了?
Let's say my Curious George is no longer curious.
我只能說,我的好奇喬治玩偶不再好奇
You are not still going over that thing.
摩妮卡,你還是無法釋懷
-This woman's living my life. -What?
-這女人過著我的生活 -什麼?
She's living my life, and she's doing it better than me.
她過著我的生活,而且過得比我好
Look at this. Look. She buys tickets to plays I wanna see.
看,她買的戲票是我一直想看的戲
She shops where I'm afraid of the salespeople.
她買的衣服是我早就想買的
-She spent $300 on art supplies. -You're not an artist.
-她花了三百塊買藝術用品 -你又不是藝術家
I might be if I had the supplies.
如果有藝術用品,我或許已是個藝術家
I mean,I could do all this stuff. Only I don't.
我本來可以的,只是現在不是
Oh,Monica,come on. You do cool things.
摩妮卡,別洩氣,你做的工作很酷
Really? Let's compare,shall we?
真的?我們來做比較,好嗎?
Oh,it's so late for "shall we."
現在說「好嗎」有點太遲了
Do I horseback ride in the park?
我到過公園騎馬嗎?
-Do I take classes at the New School? -No.
-我在新學校上過課嗎? -沒有
She's got everything I want, and she doesn't have my mother.
她擁有我想要的一切,而且她沒有我媽
-How about Joey Paponi? -No,still too ethnic.
-喬依帕波尼如何? -不好,太有種族意味了
-My agent wants a more neutral name. -Joey Switzerland?
-我的經紀人認為,我該取個中立一點的名字 -喬伊瑞士?
Plus,I think it should be Joe. Joey makes me sound like I'm this big:
而且,我應該就是喬, 喬伊讓我感覺…這麼大
Which I'm not.
可我不是
Joe,Joe,Joe Stalin?
喬…喬斯大林?
Stalin.
斯大林
Do I know that name? It sounds familiar.
我認識這名字嗎?聽得很熟悉
Well,it does not ring a bell with me.
我沒印象
But you're more plugged into that show business thing.
但是你是深深陷在表演事業之中了啊
Joe Stalin.
喬斯大林
You know,that's pretty good.
這名字很好
You might wanna try Joseph.
或許你想試試喬瑟夫
Joseph Stalin.
喬瑟夫斯大林
-I think you'd remember that. -Yes.
-我好像記得這個名字 -是的
Bye Bye Birdie, starring Joseph Stalin.
「別了,鳥兒」喬瑟夫斯大林主演
Joseph Stalin is the Fiddler on the Roof.
「屋頂上的提琴手」中的喬瑟夫斯大林
Hi. Yes,this is Monica Geller.
對,我是摩妮卡蓋勒
I'm taking some classes with you, and I was wondering what they were.
我想有在你們那裡上課,我想知道是哪些課
I've had a recent head injury and certain numbers
我最近頭部受傷,只記得一些數字了
Barbecue. Oh,did l? See,there you go.
野外烤肉.哦,我應該去嗎?好的
-What are you doing? -All right,great.
-你在幹什麼? -太好了,謝謝
Great. Thanks a lot. I'm going to tap class.
太棒了,非常感謝,我要去上踢踏舞課
To dance with the woman that stole your card?
和偷你信用卡的人一起跳踢踏?
To see what she looks like.
這樣你就可以知道她長什麼樣子
I'm sure her picture's up at the post office.
我可以肯定她的照片就掛在郵局裡面
I should get to see who she is.
我應該去看看她是何方神聖
You're kind of losing it here. This is becoming a weird obsession.
摩妮卡,你有點失去理智了, 你被這件事所完全操控
This is madness,I tell you.
我跟你說,這叫做瘋狂
For the love of God,Monica, don't do it.
上帝保佑,摩妮卡別這麼做
Thank you.
謝謝
-What do you think? -Lots of things.
-你們怎麼認為? -很多
-Which one is she? -May I help you?
-你認為是哪一個? -我能幫你們什麼嗎?
No,thanks. We're just here to observe.
謝謝,我們是來參觀的
You don't observe a dance class. You dance a dance class.
舞蹈課不是參觀來的,舞蹈課來跳舞的
Spare shoes are over there.
那兒有舞鞋
What does she mean?
什麼意思?
I think she means "You dance a dance class."
我想她是叫我們進去跳
-Come on,come on,come on. -Really?
-來吧,來吧,來吧 -真的?
Do you see anybody you think could be me?
有看見我的分身嗎?
Last time there were yogurt containers lying around after class.
各位,上回有人在教室留下酸乳空瓶
-Let's not have that happen again. -She could be you.
-希望別再發生那種事 -她可能是你
Let's get started.
開始吧
Five,six. Five,six,seven,eight.
五,六,五,六,七,八
-Okay,I'm not getting this. -I'm totally getting it.
-我跟不上 -我完全融人
Do you ever feel like you're so uncoordinated?
你不會覺得,自己有時毫無協調感嗎?
What? You click when they click.
怎麼了?只要他們踢的時候你踢就是了
All right,everyone grab a partner.
各位找個舞伴
All right. And my dead mother said you are it. I'm with Rachel.
我死去的媽說就是你,我和瑞秋
Great,it's gym class all over again.
這下可好,體育課的舊事又重演了
You can come up to the front and dance with me.
無所謂,你過來和我一起跳
Why don't I just take off my clothes and have a nightmare?
我何不脫下衣服來場惡夢?
It's okay,it's okay. I'm here, I'm here. I'm so sorry I'm late.
沒關係,我來了抱歉,我遲到
Okay,here I am. So who's the new tense girl?
來了,那個緊張的新人是誰?
-She's your partner. -Hi,I'm Monica.
-你的舞伴 -我叫摩妮卡
Oh,Monica.
摩妮卡
Hi,I'm Mon
我叫摩…
-Nana. -Monana.
-…娜娜 -摩娜娜
-It's Dutch. -You're kidding.
-是荷蘭人的名字 -你在開玩笑吧
I spent three years in Amsterdam.
我在阿姆斯特丹住了三年
Pennsylvania Dutch.
我是賓夕法尼亞州的荷蘭人
And we're dancing. Five,six,seven,eight.
開始吧.五,六,七,八
Hi.
嗨
-Hey. Where have you been? -I just got back from the vet.
-你上哪兒去了 -我剛從獸醫回來
She's not gonna make you wear a big plastic cone?
她沒叫你戴那種塑膠套吧?
She says Marcel's humping is not a phase.
她說馬修亂性不是暫時的
Apparently,he's reached sexual maturity.
顯然它已性成熟
Hey,he beat you.
嘿,它超過你呢
She says,as time goes on, he's gonna start getting violent.
她說它會越來越暴力,侵略性越來越強
So,what does this mean?
這代表什麼?
I have to give him up.
我們不能再養它了
I can't believe it. This sucks.
我真不敢相信,這真是太扯了
You just got him. How could he be an adult already?
我不懂,你才剛養它,它怎會突然成熟了?
I know. One day he's this little thing...
我知道,之前它只是個小東西
...and then he's this little thing I can't get off my leg.
不知不覺中它就緊抓住我的腿不放的小東西
Isn't there any way to keep him?
你沒有任何辦法再飼養它嗎?
No. The vet said unless he's in a place...
沒辦法,獸醫說除非有個地方…
...where he has regular access...
…讓它獲得正常的…
...to some monkey loving...
…猴愛
... he's just gonna get vicious.
…否則它會變得愈來愈殘暴
I just gotta get him into a zoo.
我得將它送到動物園
-How do you get a monkey into a zoo? -I know.
-你如何把它送進動物園? -我知道
No,that's popes into a Vokswagen.
不,那是教皇進入大眾汽車
We're applying to a lot. Our first choice would be a big state zoo.
我們到處申請, 當然大型州立動物園是優先考慮
You know,like San Diego. Right?
比方說聖地牙哥動物園
But that may just be a pipe dream. He's out-of-state.
那可能只是遙不可及的夢想,因為它在加州
My vet knows someone at Miami, so that's a possibility.
獸醫說她認識邁阿密的朋友,或許有可能
But that's two blocks from the beach. It's a total party zoo.
那兒似乎離海灘只有兩條街, 一定是個瘋狂動物園
We found the girl.
我們找到她了
-Did you call the cops? -We took her to lunch.
-你們喊警察了嗎? -沒有,我們和她吃午餐
Oh,your own brand of vigilante justice.
你們自己的「自治正義」
Are you insane? This woman stole from you.
你瘋了?那女人偷了你的東西
She stole. She's a stealer.
她偷東西,她是個小偷
After you're with this woman for 10 minutes,you forget that.
和這女人相處十分鐘後, 你就會把這些全忘了
I mean,she's this astounding person with this amazing spirit.
她簡直是奇女子,振奮人心
Which she probably stole from some cheerleader.
她可能是從某位啦啦隊隊員那兒偷來的
-Take off their hats. -Popes in a Vokswagen.
-脫下他們的帽子 -大眾車上的教皇
I love that joke.
我喜歡這個笑話
-No way. No way did you do this. -Monana was very brave.
-不可能,你不可能這麼做 -摩娜娜相當勇敢
We told them we were the Gundersons in room 61 5...
我說我們是615房的岡氏姐妹
...only to find out the Boston Celtics had the entire floor.
結果波士頓塞爾提克已包下整個六樓
When they saw that we're short and have breasts....
他們知道我們又矮又有胸部時
They threw us out. I was thrown out of a hotel. Me.
他們就把我們轟出來,我被轟出飯店,我
Go,Monana.
幹得好,摩娜娜
You ladies are not the only ones living the dream.
不是只有你們活在夢中
I get to go pour coffee for people I don't know. Don't wait up.
我得去為我不認識的人倒咖啡,不用等我了
Oh,by the way...
對了
...tomorrow we're auditioning for a Broadway show.
明天我們要去參加百老匯的試演
-Excuse me? -There's an open call for Cats.
-什麼? -「貓」劇還有一個缺額
I'm thinking we sing "Memories"...
我想我們可以去唱「回憶」
...and make complete fools of ourselves. What do you say?
讓自己當個傻子,如何?
No,no,no. Remember who you're dealing with here.
不,記得你身旁的人是誰
I can't even stand in front of a tap class.
我和你不一樣 我連站在踢踏舞教室前都有困難
That's because of your Amish background.
因為你有阿米許的血統
-What? -You're Pennsylvania Dutch,right?
-什麼? -你不是賓州荷蘭人嗎?
Right. Till I bought a blow dryer. Then I was shunned.
對,直到我買了吹風機被逐出村裡
I was just like you. And then,one day, I saw a movie that changed my life.
我過去也和你一樣 有一天我看了出改變我人生的電影
Did you ever see Dead Poets Society?
看過春風化雨嗎?
I thought that movie was so incredibly boring.
我認為這電影實在是太…無聊了
That thing at the end where the kid...
那孩子在電影的結局時…
...kills himself because he can't be in the play?
…自殺了.只因他無法演出話劇?
It's like,"Kid,wait a year. Leave home,do some community theater."
這是在幹什麼? 他再等一年離家,到社區話劇團去
I thought,"That's two hours of my life that I'm never getting back."
走出電影院時我想, 我這逝去兩小時的生命,永遠不再回
That scared me more than all the other crap I was afraid to do.
這想法震驚了我,從此我便及時行樂
Wow. Then I would definitely not recommend Mrs. Doubtfire.
那麼我不敢推薦「窈窕奶爸」了
Oh,God.
上帝
We didn't get into Scranton.
我們進不了斯克蘭頓了
That was,like,our safety zoo.
那是我們保底的動物園
They take,like,dogs and cows.
他們連狗和牛都收
See,I don't know who this is harder on,me or him.
我不懂是我還是它比較難受
I'd say that chair's taking the brunt of it.
我想應該椅子最可憐
Marcel. Marcel. Marcel,no.
馬修,馬修,馬修…不
Good boy. See? How can nobody want him?
乖,為何沒人要它?
Somebody will.
一定有人會要的
You know,there already is a Joseph Stalin.
早就有人叫喬瑟夫斯大林了
You're kidding.
開什麼玩笑
Apparently,he was this Russian dictator who slaughtered people.
顯然他是屠殺各種民族的俄國獨裁者
-You'd think you would've known that. -You'd think I would've.
-你怎麼會不知道. -你怎麼認為我知道
Hey,how about Joey Heatherton?
嗨,喬伊.漢密爾頓
Come on,I told you I don't wanna go back to Joey.
拜託,我告訴過你不要用回喬伊
What do you think a good stage name for me would be?
你認為我該取什麼藝名?
Flame Boy.
火焰男孩
Where exactly is your zoo?
你的動物園在哪兒?
Well,it's technically not a zoo,per se.
就技術上而言不算是動物園
It's more of an interactive wildlife experience.
而是一種互動式野生動物體驗
Let me ask you some questions about Marcel.
我想請教你幾個關於馬修的問題
-Does he fight with other animals? -No,no. He's very docile.
-它會和其他動物打架嗎? -不會的,它非常溫馴
Even if he were cornered?
如果被逼進角落裡去時呢?
Well,I don't know. Why?
我不知道,幹嘛問?
How is he at handling small objects?
它掌控小東西的能力為何?
He can hold a banana, if that's what you mean.
它會拿香蕉,如果你是這意思的話
What about a hammer or a small blade?
鐵槌或小刀呢?
Why would he need a blade?
為什麼?為何要小刀?
If he's up against an animal with horns...
面對獅虎或有角的動物
...you got to give him something.
你得拿些東西給它自我防衛
Otherwise,it's just cruel.
否則就太殘忍了
-He got into San Diego. -What?
-它能去聖地牙哥了 -什麼?
We came back from our walk. The phone was ringing....
我們散步回來聲見電話鈴響
He's in.
然後它就錄取了
Did you hear that,Marcel? San Diego. San Diego.
聽見沒,馬修,是聖地牙哥
You're making a mistake. San Diego's good...
你大錯特錯了,聖地牙哥環境良好沒錯
... but I'll start him off against a blind rabbit...
如果你把它交給我 我就能訓練它對抗瞎眼的兔子
...and give you 20% of the gate.
而且我還可以給你百分之二十的門票收入
Where have you been?
你到底跑哪兒去了?
Monica and I just crashed an embassy party.
我和摩妮卡剛跑去參加大使館舞會
I think I kissed an archbishop.
我想我吻了大主教
But,of course, it could've been a chef.
當然,他們有自己的廚師
-Are you drunk? -No.
-你喝醉了? -才沒有呢
-I'm lying. I am so drunk. -Oh,God.
-騙你的,我醉醺醺的 -天哪
You know what? You could've called.
摩妮卡,你該打通電話回來的
I've been worried Monica.
我一直在家裡擔心你
Water rules.
好過癮
Yes. Yes,it does.
沒錯
The restaurant called. They wanna know if you're showing up for work.
餐廳今天又來電了, 他們想知道你還要不要去上班
Nope. Going to the Big Apple Circus today.
不去.我今天要去大蘋果馬戲團
You're gonna lose your job. This is not you.
你快丟掉工作了,你變了
No,it is me.
不,這正是我
I'm not just the person who fluffs the pillows...
我不只是那種必須拍松枕頭
...and pays the bills right away.
帳單一來立刻去繳款的人
You know,when I'm with her, I'm so much more than that.
和她在一起,我就超越了那種人
I'm Monana.
我是摩娜娜
Hello? Yes,she is. Hold on a second please.
對,她在,等等
Monana,it's for you. The credit card people.
摩娜娜,你的電話,信用卡公司打來的
Hello.
你好
Yes?
是嗎?
Oh,my God.
天那
-Thanks. -What?
-謝謝. -怎麼啦?
They've arrested Monica.
他們已逮到摩妮卡
-Hi. -Hi.
-嗨.-嗨
How are you?
你好嗎?
Not too bad. Fortunately,blue's my color.
不太糟,幸好我喜歡藍色
How did you know I was here?
你怎會知道我在這兒?
Because I'm Monica Geller.
因為我是摩妮卡蓋勒
It was my credit card you were using.
你用的是我的信用卡
That I was not expecting.
真是沒想到
I want you to know, I didn't turn you in.
我想讓你知道,去報案的人不是我
-Thanks. -No,thank you.
-謝謝你 -不,我要謝謝你
You have given me so much.
你帶給我太多了
I'd never have gotten to sing...
如果不是你,我就不可能…
... "Memories" at the Winter Garden Theater.
…在冬園劇場唱「回憶」
Actually,you only got to sing "Memo"
老實說你只開口唱了「回」而已
I can't believe you're here. What will I do without you?
我不敢相信你會在這兒 失去你我該怎麼辦?
Who's gonna crash parties with me?
誰會和我去大使館宴會
Who's gonna take me to the Big Apple Circus?
誰帶我去大蘋果馬戲團?
I started my day by peeing in front of 25 other women...
我在25個女人面前尿尿展開一天的生活
...and you're worried about who'll take you to the circus?
你卻擔心沒人帶你去看馬戲?
Well,not worried, you know,just wondering.
不是擔心,只是懷疑
There's nothing to wonder about.
沒什麼好懷疑的
You'll go back to being who you were. That's who you are.
你繼續做你自己,因為那才是真正的你
-Not necessarily. -Yes,necessarily.
-那沒必要呀 -那很必要
I don't know what it is. Maybe it's the Amish thing.
我不知道是為什麼 或許和你是阿米許人有關
-I'm not actually Amish. -Really? Then why are you like that?
-我不是阿米許人 -真的?為何你那麼怪?
-You,by the door,in or out? -ln.
-門旁的那個,加不加入? -加人
-You're getting it all wrong. -But at least I'm doing it.
-後面的,你完全跳錯了 -至少我在跳
This is the final boarding call for Flight 67...
這是飛往聖地牙哥67次航班的
... to San Diego at gate 42A.
最後一次登機通知
Okay,goodbye,little monkey guy. All right,I wrote you this poem.
再見,猴子小伙.好的,我會給你寫詩的
Okay,but don't eat it till you get on the plane.
上飛機後才能吃
Thank you,Aunt Phoebe.
謝謝你,菲比阿姨
Okay,bye,champ.
再見了
There'll be a lot of babes in San Diego...
我知道聖地牙哥那兒,你將有許多漂亮美眉
... but remember, there's also a lot to learn.
記得要學習的也很多
I don't know what to say,Ross. It's a monkey.
我不知該說什麼,羅斯,它是一隻猴子
Just say what you feel,Joey.
說出你的感覺就成了
-Marcel,I'm hungry. -That was good.
-馬修,我餓了 -這句不錯
Marcel,this is for you.
馬修,這是給你的
It's just,you know,something...
給你,你知道的
...to do on the plane.
在飛機上玩的
If you don't mind, I'd like a moment alone.
如果不介意我想和它獨處
-Oh,sure. Absolutely. -Go ahead.
-當然可以. -繼續
Marcel,come here. Come here. Come here.
馬修,過來,過來,過來
Well,buddy...
小兄弟
...this is it.
就這樣了
Just a couple of things I wanted to say.
我只想說幾句話
I'm really gonna miss you.
我會想你的
You know,I'm never gonna forget about you.
我不會忘記你的
You've been more than just a pet to me.
在我心中你不只是一隻寵物
You've been more like a Okay. Marcel.
你更是…馬修
Would you leave my leg alone?
能放開我的腿嗎?
Would you stop humping me for two seconds?
能暫時不要亂來嗎?
Okay,would you just take him away? Just take him.
馬修…帶它走好嗎?帶它走
Oh,that I were a glove upon that hand...
希望我是你手上的手套
...that I might touch thy cheek.
這樣我就能撫摸你的臉頰
-That's fine. Thank you. -Next.
-行,謝謝. -下一位
I'll be reading for the role of Mercutio.
我來試演「馬丘修」角色的
-Name? -Holden McGroin.
-名字? -麥克葛羅尼